Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 9th 2024.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: No Scott, and this is geek nice tonight.
Speaker 1: We were talking about games at the beach Like the sandy beach.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Scott have you ever been stung by a wasp?
Speaker 0: I've been stung by a bee.
Speaker 1: Wasn't a beer a yellow jacket.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was a bee because Basically, I was playing wiffle ball and my brother was battin and I was pitching Right, and there's a bee comes out of the ground because it lives.
Speaker 0: it was a bee that lives in the ground.
Speaker 1: That could be a yellow jacket, but it could also be a bee.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it comes out of the ground that it starts buzzing around him and he starts swinging the wiffle ball at it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what?
Speaker 0: That's his own damn fault And I'm like what the fuck is wrong with ya.
Speaker 1: But I was a kid if I saw a wasp or a bee that looked at that was remotely coming near us.
Speaker 0: So so if he finishes swinging the bat at the at the the pointy insect and then I'm getting ready to pitch and Suddenly right under my chin like right, you know here Flat part that aims straight down is like doink And I went smack and it basically you could see it was like, you know, black and yellow stripes like a ball shape basically the spiky part and half of its ass.
Speaker 0: Like cartoonishly we're cartoonishly stick it out.
Speaker 0: It was like a spike and a half and a half a sphere.
Speaker 0: The rest of it was gone.
Speaker 0: cuz I smacked it and I pulled it out.
Speaker 0: Thankfully, I'm not allergic.
Speaker 0: But well, I mean, I think that's the only time I've been stung by a bee.
Speaker 0: I've been stung by Mosquitoes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no one time I was bitten by something unknown.
Speaker 1: Ooh Specifically about the the kind of bug that has a stinger on the back who isn't a scorpion Any kind of bug in that category?
Speaker 0: I Mean, I guess it was a bee had a stinger of some kind.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a wasp or a hornet or anything.
Speaker 1: I got stung by a wasp once.
Speaker 1: I got stung by a yellow jacket once and mine was.
Speaker 1: I'm just standing there.
Speaker 1: I'm like Anna, you know those play sets with monkey bars and stuff that you have in the backyard in the suburbs.
Speaker 1: We had a big one of those in the backyard.
Speaker 1: I'm standing on it and I feels a little tiny prick on my toe when I look down and there's a yellow jacket and it has stung my pinky toe Just on its own.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm just standing there and I'd never been stung before and for a moment.
Speaker 1: I thought that wasn't so bad Huh, and then it started to hurt like a motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the pain isn't really from the stinging.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the physical sting the pain is from whatever venom the thing has.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we're up.
Speaker 1: we were upstate at a good barbecue with some friends hanging out talking about video games for hanging out outside and Every time someone walks outside.
Speaker 1: We're warned watch out.
Speaker 1: There's a wasps nest on the left side of this one bench.
Speaker 1: Just don't like don't sit right there.
Speaker 0: Why didn't they go spray it with deadly chemicals prior to their barbecue?
Speaker 1: There's like three wasps in it so little.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I'm not gonna go and pester insects that aren't you know Like?
Speaker 0: I guess it was if it was the the lantern flies, yeah, they're right Yes, they're a problem.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know if it's just like a spiders or some ants or whatever who cares, right?
Speaker 1: But if it's ones that are going to attack people was just and it's like you've got an enemy airstrip filled with fighter jets Just like sitting next to you, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly, and it's like okay if it was like out in my woods or something or like, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's like if I'm having people over or like children are gonna be there or there's like a reason.
Speaker 0: It's like if they're just deadly or not to be deadly but dangerous right or you know aggressive Potentially aggressive.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna bother them just because of that.
Speaker 0: But if there's gonna be people that are gonna be near them because it's my property I'm gonna do something in that then it's like alright, you've got a problem here.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna come at you with my Human weapons, but everyone's being good.
Speaker 1: Everyone's avoiding it and this isn't a story of someone went and messed with it.
Speaker 1: No one did anything.
Speaker 1: I ended up sitting for a while kind of right near it.
Speaker 1: But you know I'm not worried about wasps.
Speaker 1: and and wasps will generally leave you alone unless they perceive that you have slighted them in some way.
Speaker 1: and there's one at one cool dude who he knows hanging out at the party and He has never been stung by any such insect in his life And any of course he was stung by such an insect.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, and he was.
Speaker 1: he Respected the wasp had her tale of wasp stings suck and wasps are assholes.
Speaker 1: So he was giving this thing Appropriate birth.
Speaker 1: He was being the most careful of anyone at this party to go nowhere near where the wasps are.
Speaker 0: and One of the wasps you could have you could have known well in advance.
Speaker 0: He could have taken wagers He could.
Speaker 0: I guess he could have stayed inside the whole time to avoid and I feel like the wasps would have gotten inside and gotten.
Speaker 1: It's like the wasps.
Speaker 1: They waited for their moment because he didn't fucking do anything and at one point he's not even I wasn't the one who swung The bat at the V, right?
Speaker 1: This wasps flies out of the nest flies toward him who has not even been near the nest in a while and just stings him right on the foot.
Speaker 0: No, listen, this could be.
Speaker 0: you know with the global warming's right as New York becomes closer to you know What say a Carolina was over time or a Virginia or a more southerly place.
Speaker 0: We're gonna get more, you know things like that, but it's like warm weather makes people angrier too.
Speaker 0: I imagine.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I'm like, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't tell the story of random freakout I see in Midtown every time we do a show but I see a lot of random freakouts in the street, right?
Speaker 1: It's well the summer.
Speaker 0: madness is well known and it's we know with his evidence is yes It makes people more aggressive and angry.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to wager it has the same effect on Animals of various kinds, but wasps are already maximally angry.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like a gas turns into a plasma.
Speaker 1: a wasp turns into a some new form of terror.
Speaker 1: but his reaction to being stung was Amazing because basically at this party we determined that pretty much everyone there had been stung by something at some point And like.
Speaker 1: I didn't think about the fact that as an adult like if I get stung by something again now I know I'm not allergic and I kind of know the deal like.
Speaker 1: I know to expect he'd never been stung by anything before.
Speaker 1: So we so he's like, oh that really hurts.
Speaker 1: and then he sits down He's like so you've all been stung by these kinds of things before.
Speaker 1: What should I expect?
Speaker 0: And we start.
Speaker 1: Hey, yeah, we start walking through like well in about ten minutes It's gonna hurt way more than you think it's gonna hurt.
Speaker 1: and that's only the beginning.
Speaker 1: and then we start walking.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: it was funny to watch this this like.
Speaker 1: tell me what to expect and all of the wise and elders Who've experienced this before imparting their wisdom one by one as and we all recounted our experiences of I got stung.
Speaker 1: But it was interesting that everyone we talked to at this party had been stung as a kid except this one guy
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: it's like
Speaker 0: a regular maybe maybe that was that guy had like a special strategy Become a memory on purpose to tell a story about not getting stung and then get stung.
Speaker 0: That's like next level, you know,
Speaker 1: like I remember because when I was in high school I remember talking to people at a party and I just remember this conversation where everyone was talking about how everyone breaks their arm at some point when they're a kid and that's like a rite of passage.
Speaker 1: and it was weird to me because Everyone at this party had broken their arm at some point and they thought it was weird that I'd never broken my arm.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile all my real friends like who weren't at this party?
Speaker 1: all the weirdo nerds None of them had ever broken their arm before.
Speaker 1: and it was weird to me how many of these kids had broken their arms.
Speaker 1: But I think the reason they had all broken their arms We lived in Michigan and this was the kind of place where a lot of parents had trampolines.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the trampoline was responsible for the supermajority of all of those broken arms.
Speaker 1: Hmm anyway, I got any news, of course you do because Nintendo Direct happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was already like a super long time ago.
Speaker 0: We just haven't done a podcast Since then.
Speaker 0: it was like in June maybe but yeah, there was a Nintendo Direct and There are many things announced that this is Nintendo Direct, but we'll only talk about you know, the big ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So the first big one is that they're gonna make a another game in the Mario and Luigi's RPG series right which started off with the Superstar Saga And they haven't had one of those in like a decade or more right a long-ass time.
Speaker 0: So that's you know a whole new game not a remake.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: and by the way, I think you can play the Superstar Saga on the GBA Nintendo online app Because I've actually never played it.
Speaker 0: It's they're really good.
Speaker 0: I know they're really.
Speaker 0: they don't they don't they don't take that long.
Speaker 0: they're basically just JRPGs, but with Mario and Luigi obviously and you do you know, it's sort of like Mario RPG where you sort of have to do timed button presses.
Speaker 0: Right, you see the same mechanic also with like Paper Mario, which is also an RPG.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's just a different twist on the same thing.
Speaker 0: I think what else was interesting?
Speaker 1: there was The Nintendo World Championships looks really fun because I do it's right.
Speaker 0: So the Nintendo World Championships is gonna be like $30.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was about to say the problem is it looks really fun and I like that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: But I can experience that kind of thing like at Magfest with their championships Like that little emulator thing they have set up with the special challenges.
Speaker 0: I think it's only worth it if you're really a speed runny hyper competitive type person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, otherwise, it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is a shame because it looks fun.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't look $30 fun Considering that its focus does seem to be like you said more on speed running and technique and less on like.
Speaker 1: Here's a weird challenge.
Speaker 1: beat bubble man.
Speaker 1: You've only got quick man's weapon and you started half health.
Speaker 1: go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they added some games more, you know, they the zero Metro zero mission.
Speaker 0: Yeah Isn't a great way to play Metroid 1. if you haven't played that is on the Nintendo online app for GBA.
Speaker 0: Also the the link to the past GBA version that includes like the four swords minigame is on there And they're gonna make a way to do that part online.
Speaker 0: But the thing is that's the four swords like sort of like side game.
Speaker 0: It's not really.
Speaker 1: it's not the real full length It's not the GameCube.
Speaker 0: four swords is the real deal.
Speaker 0: It's not on there.
Speaker 0: They also made a new app.
Speaker 0: That's there's now two Nintendo 64 apps on your switch the regular one and a separate one just for like rated m games.
Speaker 1: I you that was my news a long time ago on geek nights when they announced that in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the perfect the only games in there are perfect dark and turak.
Speaker 0: yeah, which are You know, but um, really big news is that you know Marvel all the Marvel Capcom games, you know Since MVC 3 came out which I don't know how big a deal that was, but I don't really see people care about that anymore.
Speaker 0: But all the MVC games have been sort of a in a limbo Right with the mostly because of the rights because you got Marvel characters and Capcom characters, right?
Speaker 0: And so it's always tricky because they make a deal when they originally make the game But then does the deal still exist for them to make a remake years later or to re-release it years later.
Speaker 0: But it seems that whatever The issues were have been sorted out and they're gonna make for all platforms not just for switch.
Speaker 0: But it was first announced at the switch Nintendo Direct the MVC fighting collection that has all of those games Except for three, I guess but all the old ones one two the ones, you know All the all of them, right and including this Punisher beat-em-up one that every new existed.
Speaker 0: So the MVC two people are super excited about that.
Speaker 1: There's a new Mario Party, which is like yeah, right I mean honestly I the Mario Parties have not done it for me in a long time At this.
Speaker 0: but there is one thing about this Mario Party that made me raise an eyebrow.
Speaker 1: I see I'm looking here cuz I didn't watch the full Nintendo Direct yet And I see it has some sort of 20 player online mode, which could be Exciting.
Speaker 1: The thing is give me a Wario Ware incorporated 20 player online game and with And we're I would pay a lot of money for that.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: here's something I want to talk about more.
Speaker 0: is that you know, they made that remake the HD remake of In the GB Links awakening which is if you have not played.
Speaker 1: if you've never played links awakening you could just play this one.
Speaker 1: It's phenomenal It's beautiful.
Speaker 1: It's basically just the exact same game.
Speaker 0: or yeah it's like, you know, there's a thing with the HD remakes like cuz.
Speaker 0: one side of me is like Why they keep making these remakes.
Speaker 0: I could just play the original game, right and that matters.
Speaker 0: I think More when the gap between the original game and the remake is less.
Speaker 0: So like they're like Metroid Prime HD remakes and it's like I got a GameCube discs, I don't really need remakes Those are just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, there's.
Speaker 0: they got a Mario RPG remake that I bought and played which I don't know was really worth $60, but OG Gameboy Right, it's like but it was a lot more friendly to play that than to play the old Super Nintendo original.
Speaker 0: But like there's a there's a Thousand year door remake and if you can just play the original I don't really see a reason to go for the remake.
Speaker 0: but if you can't just play the original because you don't have a GameCube or you're not gonna emulate or pirate or figure out whatever You got to do that remake is probably, you know, the same thing only better.
Speaker 0: But the interesting thing here is that they're making a new game called Legend of Zelda Echoes of Wisdom in which you are Zelda and You can basically copy any item and use that to solve puzzles and get around and do everything you got to do.
Speaker 0: You could watch the trailer to understand what's going on there.
Speaker 1: I think it looks real fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, it looks way fun, right and it's a lot more in line with it's.
Speaker 0: it's more like a - you know I guess it's not 2d but you know It's a lot more in line with Breath of the Wild and Tears of the Kingdom where you're you're building and making stuff Right, and so I think that's what Zelda games are like about now
Speaker 1: and I think why they made this one specifically was partly They're
Speaker 0: closer to.
Speaker 0: they like had this Garry's Mod element into Zelda Which is Oh
Speaker 1: total aside at this barbecue that there was one individual who the hill he was gonna fucking die on Was that Breath of the Wild was better in every way than Tears of the Kingdom and he hated Tears of the Kingdom.
Speaker 1: all right, and he's trying to explain this and In the same fashion as our crew when that kind of conversing half conversation happens with the one person who has that kind of Incorrect idea.
Speaker 1: every time someone walked into the room who knew this guy They'd be like, oh he's talking about his fucking bad Zelda opinions again, and they'd leave.
Speaker 0: Why was that person invited?
Speaker 0: But the point about this game All right, is that they've done something which I haven't seen done before Which is that they went and did an HD remake and then they made a sequel to the remake.
Speaker 0: And then it's not a sequel to the remake, but it's they made another date made another game on the remake engine, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you've seen for example, like Capcom has done all these Resident Evil remakes Which I highly recommend because the original Resident Evils are extremely unfun to play Control wise and interface wise and the remakes make them very playable.
Speaker 0: But imagine if they're like, all right his Resident Evil 2 HD remake.
Speaker 0: and now here's a brand new Resident Evil game.
Speaker 0: You've never seen before we're gonna use the engine that we put all that work into for that remake and I don't know why that part of why they made I know of because that links awakening remake is Absolutely beautiful.
Speaker 1: It almost has this like tilt shift putty model style.
Speaker 1: It looks so good.
Speaker 0: But if you do all the work to make an HD remake or a new remake of an old game.
Speaker 0: You've just made a new engine.
Speaker 0: Why not make new games on that engine?
Speaker 0: and it's actually.
Speaker 0: I think it's a good strategy.
Speaker 0: In fact, because you know a lot of it's hard to just make an engine from nothing.
Speaker 0: It's like the most successful game engines were always made in tandem with a game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right like unreal engine is made I know I guess unity would be an exception.
Speaker 0: There wasn't made with a game Circle in the toilet right now Yeah, but all the like.
Speaker 0: the great game engines were.
Speaker 0: someone made a game and they made an engine for that game and then that Engine got reused and all those further games are effectively mods And it's like this is exactly that.
Speaker 0: so, you know But you can start off without having to put so much effort on the game part if you're doing a remake Because the game is mostly already designed for you.
Speaker 1: But there's also illustrates something very important about the game design that this is effectively this engine.
Speaker 1: This is a 2d Zelda.
Speaker 1: the Game design and video games are still in their infancy considering they were invented in living living memory of humans who are alive today as a medium and a concept and the fact that you can basically take the Constraints of a fit of a 2d map like links awakening and there's still unplumbed depths of game design and new games Says a lot about how little we've scratched the surface of what video games could be.
Speaker 1: Imagine what video or a couple hundred years from now.
Speaker 0: Well, it also says that some little tiny game that was made for the game boy.
Speaker 0: They did a such a good job that you don't actually need to change the game very much at all.
Speaker 0: You just need to you know, make it work on modern technology.
Speaker 1: change the artwork much like think about old stories like the Odyssey.
Speaker 1: Get an HD remake of the Odyssey when Emily Wilson translated it and it's relevant today and it's still good.
Speaker 0: Yeah And so the final one is after a very long wait, right Nintendo does have a history of Announcing games at you know directs or e threes or other events that never came to pass.
Speaker 0: I remember there was like some project hammer thing and some others But in this case when this like early when the switch came out 2017, I think it's like seven years ago They announced Metroid Prime 4 and then in the next time they were like listen We had problems where you had to start from scratch.
Speaker 0: Basically, they didn't say all the details, but they basically were like, yeah We didn't like the direction it was going.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna try again with Metroid Prime 4. and then they were silent for six or seven years Yeah, and we basically said well, they're never gonna say and make an announcement that they've given up, right?
Speaker 0: They'll just not say anything.
Speaker 0: So now there's no way to know.
Speaker 0: but now they came out and they said nope.
Speaker 0: We're good Here's an actual trailer and it's like, alright.
Speaker 0: Well, that means it's ready.
Speaker 0: So it's coming out in 2025, which you have to imagine Means that it will be a launch title for the new console.
Speaker 0: Whatever it's called.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't bet against that.
Speaker 1: That's that's yeah Nintendo's pattern for a while now.
Speaker 0: Yes, and if you remember Breath of the Wild came out, you know It's like a very early.
Speaker 0: was it a launch title for switch or is very early like first week or something, but it was Simultaneously released on the Wii U right.
Speaker 0: so that I imagine Metroid Prime 4 will be similar to where it'll be on switch But also a new console.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the same time Just like Breath of the Wild was and good.
Speaker 1: Oh I didn't realize the breath of the Wii U version only renders at 720p.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: The switch version actually renders at 900 P. Yep, I think that's the only difference.
Speaker 0: That's the only difference.
Speaker 1: that I'm aware of is just you know You've got to interact with a Wii U which is a mixed bag.
Speaker 0: the controller the controller is there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in one little news Xbox cloud gaming.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice this.
Speaker 1: I just saw this news and it's I wouldn't say fascinating but it's very indicative of I think we're The triple-a.
Speaker 1: non Nintendo consoles are going long-term.
Speaker 1: Xbox cloud gaming just works on Amazon fire sticks the new ones as long as you pay for Their most expensive game pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why not?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't need an Xbox if you have this thing.
Speaker 1: It'll just work.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have the Apple TV 4k and when we use steam stream, it's like you wouldn't know Yeah that you're streaming.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, and of course be from the internet.
Speaker 0: You might know it's a little gonna be a little slower Right.
Speaker 0: It might be a little lower quality than steam streaming from inside the house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because if I stream to the living room I'm steaming streaming from a workstation with a 4080 in it.
Speaker 1: That is right literally wired physically to the same network Right depending on the game.
Speaker 0: But the thing is if you do the steam if you stream from the internet from their cloud service Yeah, you are gonna have worse network between you and them.
Speaker 0: But you got your streaming from like some mega PC that they've got up in their cloud, right?
Speaker 0: Some like mega server that's ultra powerful with who knows what GPUs up there.
Speaker 0: So, you know a little more of one a little less of the other.
Speaker 0: but yeah, I mean, you know if you think about this It's like hey people already have you know the TV that I got the smart TV function that I never use.
Speaker 1: The TV itself could do game streaming plus honestly 17 bucks a month for like the ultimate game pass thing.
Speaker 1: if that's for your bag And Xbox cost what 300 350 bucks.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think you know, you're gonna Yeah one if you instead of buying an Xbox you could pay for this for one and a half years without having to buy our console.
Speaker 0: I mean if you consider the fact that most consoles have been sold like at a loss or very low margins And then just to get you know, it's a razor blade razor deal, right and the games are where they make the money Switching all the games, you know, basically every companies has you know, the Netflix game Distribution model in their back pocket or in their front pocket or their side pocket Xbox game pass being sort of like I guess the front-runner at least right now Netflix it has games on there.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah all the people who don't need to say play games where there's no internet or You know have high-performance games or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: why would you pay hundreds and hundreds of dollars for a console to have this hardware in your house?
Speaker 0: when?
Speaker 0: The cheap hardware you already own can play every game and you don't need to worry.
Speaker 1: I Think long-term like over the next decade.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 1: The three kinds of video gaming are basically gonna be Nintendo consoles Streaming to devices like this or the PC gamers who are playing their highly specialized PC games.
Speaker 0: Well, see if you know the nerdy one continues to be an option, right?
Speaker 1: Because if you're a game to shock the nerdy one has continued to be an option.
Speaker 1: to be honest Yeah, thankful.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I'm the only one I think it.
Speaker 0: I think long-term It'll only be an option for like, you know games made by indie nerds for indie nerds and like.
Speaker 0: why would big companies?
Speaker 0: Why would they?
Speaker 0: you know if it it's like if they can get people to subscribe?
Speaker 0: Some game service.
Speaker 0: They should just make the very, you know, the minimal amount of games they need to keep people subscribed.
Speaker 0: put as much microtransactions on there as they need to to make as much money as they can and Why would they bother with the hardware or Anything else extra?
Speaker 1: I think I think about the people I know outside of like our extremely rarefied nerdy circles like co-workers.
Speaker 1: The lot of them are gamers and their families are gamers, but they either are Nintendo only PlayStation or Xbox only or PC gaming and Nintendo.
Speaker 1: I don't know anyone who's just PC gaming and I don't think I've met anyone who is PC gaming and Traditional triple-a console, but I think there's too much overlap between You know PC gaming and PlayStation slash Xbox and like.
Speaker 0: owning two of those is sort of redundant.
Speaker 0: I think so like unless you just you know, there's some people I do know who are PC gaming But they will also have a PlayStation because there's like a few PlayStation exclusives that like they're absolutely crazy about but Sony's starting to get Rid of those.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of those games that come in a PC.
Speaker 1: So yeah but anyway things Of the day.
Speaker 1: so I have two notes about this video because Recently, I was reminded of one of my favorite animated gifs of all time like top five.
Speaker 1: I animated gifs that I ever encountered in my life.
Speaker 1: It's this video.
Speaker 1: It's a very short clip of a guy Launching a tall model rocket and just as he launches it in slow motion It slowly falls over pointed directly at him and he reacts as fast as a human can To try to get out of its way and fails to do so.
Speaker 1: and it's just really funny and really short.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's like I don't know why and you were standing that close to a model rocket.
Speaker 1: I was only ever a few feet away when I launched model rockets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like usually we would.
Speaker 0: you know, as long as the wires between Would go is how I never in my life.
Speaker 1: I used to be really into rocketry.
Speaker 1: I never had the launchpad fall over.
Speaker 0: That's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would like drive into the ground but always be as far away as you know The equipment allowed us to be so I was reminded of that.
Speaker 1: So I looked around like alright internet Show me what a modern model rocket failure looks like in glorious HD and I found this video that is called High-power rocketry fail compilation and I have two observations Observation number one.
Speaker 1: Every one of these is hilarious and they're all hilarious for different reasons.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of ways it can go wrong.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: My favorites.
Speaker 0: I actually really there were no people harmed.
Speaker 1: No one's harmed either.
Speaker 1: That's very important.
Speaker 1: My two of my favorite moments from this video are very early.
Speaker 1: one is the absolutely beautiful Tintin rocket that just explodes.
Speaker 0: Well, that's like that's a tradition right?
Speaker 0: It's like even in summer camp They would always be some kids, you know a handful who would there.
Speaker 0: they would make the coolest looking rocket That was stylish or weird or amazing or not normal, right.
Speaker 0: and you know those rockets.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: you knew that they were not going to fly properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: but you really wanted them to because like they were the best one middle school I watched a really cool x-wing make it about four feet off the ground and then just turn sideways and Immediately crash into a tree.
Speaker 0: but if some kid just like made it with the kit according to the kit instructions and didn't do anything weird It's like it was very reliable.
Speaker 0: It worked perfectly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep It's like.
Speaker 0: it's like boring and uninspiring but it's like yeah, okay, but the the other one that is.
Speaker 0: why can't?
Speaker 1: So specifically is there's one where they go to launch it and the motor starts up like the rocket engine starts and then the top Just pops off with the payload and everything and then after a perfect comedic beat of nothing happening The bottom fully ignites and this like split into rocket with his parachute already out tries to fly and spins around like crazy in the air and then crashes and disintegrates.
Speaker 1: But this my second primary observation about this video and a friend of ours pointed this out immediately after I posted it.
Speaker 1: Almost every fail in this video is from what appears to be the same event Which leaves me to question the fuck was going on at this event that all like 90% of the Rockets failed?
Speaker 1: Or were there like a thousand Rockets and they just showed us the 50 that failed.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've only ever been to like summer camp events where like I said Most of the Rockets were people following the kit instructions and then a few people would you know?
Speaker 0: Make a weird one or a big one or something that would maybe may or may not work part of it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it's like at.
Speaker 1: These are not like an yeah, obviously a quest.
Speaker 1: right that's using like an a-10 or like a b12 or whatever rocket.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: These are like high-powered custom.
Speaker 1: You need a permit for this Rockets.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what these events are like.
Speaker 0: right are.
Speaker 0: how many people?
Speaker 0: is this normal for this kind of event?
Speaker 0: There's so many amateurs who aren't you know?
Speaker 1: Right because these fail like in such Baby's first rocket ways as someone who was a very into rocketry as a kid that either Nobody here knew what they were doing or they're just trying to make rockets that are way too powerful for their capabilities.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that you know, that's sort of what mod, you know model rocketry and I guess what real-world rocketry Yeah was was about in its early stages, right and when new people getting into the hobby are sort of re Experiencing that which is that it's trial and error, right?
Speaker 0: You're not just going it's it's boring and stupid to get into the hobby and then just copy someone else's and already working rocket.
Speaker 0: What's the point in that right?
Speaker 0: It's not fun or interesting.
Speaker 0: It's like you're sort of everyone's going through that trial and error phase where it's like you see how your rocket failed and you correct For it and you repeat and then you start making reliable ones.
Speaker 0: But then you know You have something specific you want to do.
Speaker 0: that's weird or different and now you have to trial and error to get that To work if it's even possible.
Speaker 1: craziest thing I ever did.
Speaker 1: and it failed.
Speaker 1: we missed.
Speaker 1: we don't even know what we hit.
Speaker 1: I launched a rocket with my parents full consent because my dad thought this was this was hilarious.
Speaker 1: We had a rocket and the goal was we tried to launch it over our neighborhood at night to egg someone's house.
Speaker 1: We wanted to hit a specific house with.
Speaker 0: really you can't aim with a rocket like you can.
Speaker 1: but And I Declared we did not do it right and we lost the rocket and we knew he don't know where it went or the egg went Or anything.
Speaker 0: well current rockets.
Speaker 0: these days people put GPS trackers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was not an option in like 1994.
Speaker 0: you don't say Can't just drop a. you know An Apple little thingy in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know you do because I watched the video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you linked me to right.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, we don't like to use the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 0: But there was SGD Q last week, right?
Speaker 0: you know AGD cues usually around, you know, New Year's magfest time and SGD cues around 4th of July every year.
Speaker 0: and last time they had a speed run from peanut butter.
Speaker 0: the dog the first time that I know of a non-human was featured as a speedrunner.
Speaker 0: and so this time and SGD Q peanut butter the dog showed up in person and I was trying to think I'm like, oh peanut butter.
Speaker 0: the dogs coming back.
Speaker 0: I wonder what game?
Speaker 0: because last time they played gyromite, which is a game that's perfect for a dog.
Speaker 1: I want to point out.
Speaker 1: when we talked about this I predicted there would basically start to become a dog percent category in that there would be more games and this is gonna become a thing.
Speaker 1: but I couldn't think of what games would be good because Gyromite is a perfect game.
Speaker 0: If you know anything about gyromite, I'm not going to explain it to you.
Speaker 0: You can look at absolutely perfect.
Speaker 0: Can't think of a perfect game for a non-human to assist in right?
Speaker 0: What game did they play?
Speaker 0: I couldn't believe Ken Griffey jr's MLB for the SNES which was the best baseball game for the Super Nintendo by far.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also the baseball simulator 1000 was a distant second.
Speaker 0: Well, that was a different kind of game.
Speaker 0: This is actual.
Speaker 1: I mean if you turned off the nonsense It was just a baseball game, but that was.
Speaker 0: it was more like an NBA Jam kind of deal.
Speaker 0: But this is this.
Speaker 0: one is a real baseball game and I'm like, holy shit.
Speaker 0: How is a dog gonna play?
Speaker 0: Yeah This game and I'm like, well the dog, you know, it's not a speedrun.
Speaker 0: rarely They're gonna play one game and that's nine innings and try to win and I Don't know if they if they scripted this it's like they scripted it extremely well and made it very believable but it Don't think it could have gotten better than it did.
Speaker 1: I mean if you understand a game very well as we know from you know I've watched a lot of A&S GDQs in my life so far.
Speaker 1: like a lot of them there are definitely games where you could come up with a path where there's a limited number of Relatively loosely timed button presses that have a huge impact and that's the cleverness finding games.
Speaker 1: You can do this, too.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this is the new bar.
Speaker 0: I won't feature GDQ on the thing of the day again Unless there's a run better than this one.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of good ones though this time.
Speaker 0: So they actually they go to the YouTube and check it out.
Speaker 1: The wand of gamelan run was the best one of gamelan run I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: I actually watched the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It wasn't painful.
Speaker 1: It was a good commentary.
Speaker 1: And of course my boy quest for glory, too.
Speaker 1: That was a good speedrun because they did fighter.
Speaker 1: Nobody does fighter.
Speaker 1: I was glad to see fight I think.
Speaker 0: well, I think it was because there was a Donation incentive to choose the class.
Speaker 0: Could have been any chance that fighter got the vote.
Speaker 1: All right Stive into this.
Speaker 1: so we did a show back on August 2nd 2018 called how to not suck at the beach And that was just talking about beating.
Speaker 0: but there's something we did an episode about outdoor like yard game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we did.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we had to have if we didn't that's easy show on lawn games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like bocce and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was about to say I'm good at bocce, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't played bocce in like a decade.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm any good at bocce anymore.
Speaker 1: We should go to Bryant Park and play bocce.
Speaker 0: We can visit as an actual bocce court in Astoria Park where the old guys play.
Speaker 0: It's like it existed a long time ago and then it got run down because no one was using it.
Speaker 0: the old guy some old guy who was way into bocce came and Renovated it on his own and there's like a little thing.
Speaker 0: They were full of bocce equipment and I've seen old guys out there playing.
Speaker 0: That's my life.
Speaker 0: That's my life's goal is to become an old man who plays bocce in the park with other old men.
Speaker 0: Yeah, get started early.
Speaker 1: the old man who referees for the other old men playing bocce.
Speaker 0: They don't referee they just yell at each other.
Speaker 0: That's how you got to do it,
Speaker 1: so we're talking today about the Venn diagram between games lawn games outdoor games which could include board games and The beach games to play at the beach because there's actually a lot of constraints At beaches to the point that we're gonna have to talk about different kinds of beaches and different seasons To really explore this.
Speaker 1: this is actually a bigger topic that I thought of but I think before we even talk about specific games The thing that I think is the most important about games at the beach.
Speaker 1: Is that most of the time?
Speaker 1: anyone who says they want to play games at the beach or brings games to play at the beach is going to fail because if you do not have a critical mass of people who are the Kinds of people who will go to a beach early in the day and stay there all day Then the odds of any game getting played approach zero Rapidly and nothing we say will matter beyond that.
Speaker 1: what I know people.
Speaker 1: I've been there watching people trying to get a game going At the beach.
Speaker 1: It's real hard.
Speaker 1: If you don't have a crew to roll with who are down for beach games Yeah, you have to play a game at the beach, right?
Speaker 0: You have to be at the beach long enough that you get your fill of going in the water.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get your fill of laying there reading.
Speaker 0: Yeah Making a sandcastle like you made the maximum sandcast You get your fill of eating an ice cream and your fill of everything that you're gonna.
Speaker 0: all beach activities have been satiated then and only then.
Speaker 0: well beach game Suddenly takes them.
Speaker 0: get get it its edge in there like huh?
Speaker 0: I guess we've done all the beach stuff, but we're still got some more hours at the beach.
Speaker 1: cuz we're here so long Let's do some beach game and I'm a gamer like gaming is one of the most important things in my life.
Speaker 1: And yet I put playing games near the bottom of my list of things I am interested in at the beach.
Speaker 1: Yet I encounter people in my life among my friend group who really think they're gonna get games to happen at the beach.
Speaker 0: Yep So the first thing for beach games is that you want to prioritize?
Speaker 0: Games that can only be played at the beach such as a beach volleyball.
Speaker 0: Yeah Did you know beach soccer is like a super popular sport?
Speaker 1: I did not but now I want to play a Beach soccer.
Speaker 0: It's it's like sand soccer.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I actually watched a video about a dude who was from I forget which South American country He's from but like he moved to Japan to play beach soccer in Japan like somewhat Professionally like it would I guess it compensates enough that it was worth moving countries.
Speaker 1: Oh, I really want to play this now.
Speaker 0: Beach soccer.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't like.
Speaker 0: respect soccer the sport in general, but you know, it's fun Real fun to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would play it.
Speaker 0: But the introduction of the sand as a surface Dramatically changes just everyday sports that without you know, the same way that ice transforms field hockey, right?
Speaker 0: You know beach volleyball is completely different from gym volleyball, right?
Speaker 0: You've got the elements the wind from the ocean coming in.
Speaker 0: you've got you know, the surface.
Speaker 0: if you can't like run You got less people.
Speaker 0: It's usually two on two.
Speaker 0: It's not usually what's regular volleyball?
Speaker 0: six on six, right?
Speaker 0: I think It's.
Speaker 0: you know, it's a lot harder to jump when the surface is different, but it's also easier to fall.
Speaker 0: Right, so you could do a lot more dives right in not that they don't dive in the gym.
Speaker 0: They just get hurt.
Speaker 0: Okay, right but in beach volleyball they're not armored up with all kinds of knee pads and elbow pads.
Speaker 0: Well, also no cleats.
Speaker 1: you are barefoot.
Speaker 1: So like even like why I've watched some videos just now Goddamn, the techniques have even like kicking and passing.
Speaker 1: It's a totally different game.
Speaker 0: The point is beach volleyball is a distinct sport even in the Olympics from regular volleyball with good reason.
Speaker 1: But I think this is this opens up to broader advice for gamers in general because I see this problem with gamer nerds a lot.
Speaker 1: They will be in a place Context situation that itself should be the focus and yet they will bring Games that could be played anytime any place in any environment and almost pollute The experience they could be having and then play terraforming Mars like on a mountaintop when they could be enjoying the mountaintop.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's like listen after your mountaintop You're still gonna go to some cabin and that's when you can bring out your terraforming Mars.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: There is a spot it splash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one.
Speaker 0: there are some games I know that can be played, you know in wet areas.
Speaker 1: I think that's the core you.
Speaker 1: it has to be games that either can only be played at the beach or That are in some way enhanced by Being at the beach spotted.
Speaker 1: splash is like that because think about the way we play spotted with the big mass of people yelling at Each other double-fisted bomb mode.
Speaker 1: do that in four feet of water.
Speaker 1: You got a fucking game going
Speaker 0: Because you lose pieces in the water,
Speaker 1: I mean if you want a special version
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to play an actual like tabletop II game at the beach I would recommend a game that has like tiles something like hive All right, and you know cards always get blown away in the wind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Right do?
Speaker 0: you could play chess or a backgammon?
Speaker 0: right that those have heavy pieces.
Speaker 0: Just make sure your dice are heavy enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so something like that If you're doing that during your lay on in under your umbrella time, you know instead of reading a book.
Speaker 1: that's acceptable Yeah, but again, that's that's a situation where you're primarily enjoying the beach and while you're there you're playing some backgammon Like you're not exactly.
Speaker 1: you're not prioritizing the backgammon overlaid in the beach.
Speaker 1: You're kind of idly taking your turn That's right.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The other thing you can do is if you have a portable gaming device, you know I don't like to use the phone too much at the beach because it gets hot.
Speaker 0: it gets hot Yeah, and phones don't like getting heated up so much.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know, the phone will complain like I'm not charging anymore It's too hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also resume charging later.
Speaker 0: It's no.
Speaker 1: greens on any modern devices are easy to see in bright sunlight.
Speaker 1: So unless you're at the beach in the evening You're probably like anyway, you can get.
Speaker 0: one advantage would be to use a Game Boy Advance, which is perfect because And you can basically replace your book with that right and the sunlight shining on to it makes it easier to use Young.
Speaker 1: to remember the Game Boy Advance You needed to point the fucking Sun at it to be able to see it in any context.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah a portable gaming device.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't bring my switch to the beach.
Speaker 1: No, there's the sand is gonna get in that thing.
Speaker 0: No matter what a tiger LCD game, perhaps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll dispose of a game.
Speaker 0: You don't care a Little a little one one dollar digital.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see with an LCD screen.
Speaker 1: But I think games you're gonna prioritize sports and activities type games over video games.
Speaker 1: I don't get the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's hit the ball back and forth without a net.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Just have two rackets in a ball.
Speaker 1: There's Throw throw the nerf ball football that has wings on the back The various forms of dunk game full contact dunking lots of different names and rules for that.
Speaker 1: It's actually a game I really like to play.
Speaker 1: but as we get older don't drown each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't get lifeguards to yell at you.
Speaker 0: Find find the best seashell always, you know Catch a crab.
Speaker 0: Who catches the best crab?
Speaker 0: catch crab first Marco Polo.
Speaker 0: great for pools not great for beaches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Marco Polo is really hard to play on the beach Especially if waves are coming.
Speaker 1: it's like you don't see them and you know I have played Marco Polo at the beach and had a lot of fun But we played it.
Speaker 1: You're basically you're in the the really shallow water only and it's more a game of like sneaking Blindfolded tag and it's more about just making the person who's blindfolded trip.
Speaker 1: Like that's mostly what you're doing.
Speaker 0: Yep You know, it's really.
Speaker 0: they just run on the beach cuz like, you know It's like in a race or whatever.
Speaker 0: cuz running on sand is dramatically different running anywhere else.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not really a game.
Speaker 0: But what am I as long as it's not - you got a thing.
Speaker 0: is you got to watch out for the hot sand?
Speaker 1: Yep, but also if you're running the firm sand instead of the hot sand like the sand that's wet and you're not.
Speaker 1: You're not a person who knows a lot and is good at this and has experience You're going to give yourself the worst blisters you've ever had in your life and that's gonna be the end of you.
Speaker 0: Yep One thing if you have a dog you can play throw a disc right discs.
Speaker 0: throwing this is excellent at the beach.
Speaker 1: I mean just throwing one is one of the best beach activities.
Speaker 0: There is I think yep, of course, you know surfing Any kind of boarding in the water activity, you know water ski Parasail all those which I have not done too much of those in my life, but they're there I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: they don't seem too dangerous as I wouldn't do it where there's like crazy dangerous waves You know, I would do it where it's kind of moderate and I know I'm okay enough at swimming that I wouldn't hopefully wouldn't drown.
Speaker 1: Now, of course one thing I know we've been basically talking only about the kind of beach We go to the most often which is the.
Speaker 1: it is super hot out.
Speaker 1: you try to be there on the hottest possible day.
Speaker 1: it's a beach that is Sand like sand sand everywhere and you're sitting in the sand with an umbrella of some kind.
Speaker 1: But there are other kinds of beaches that I think are very different game environments like in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: You know lake beaches like big lake beaches.
Speaker 1: often you'd be there when it's cooler.
Speaker 1: often There are picnic tables and like cabanas and shacks and things like right next to or on the beach There's places to sit where it's.
Speaker 1: I actually would play a full-on Tabletopper card game like on a table in a semi shelter that just happens to be on the beach.
Speaker 1: But that's a very different kind of beach and that's very basically the equivalent of playing a board game on a camping trip.
Speaker 1: It's just the beach is there instead of the forest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the beat that kind of beach doesn't compete so much right with with its enticing oceanic waters.
Speaker 1: It's more of a setting you could play a game in and it's like the backdrop to it as opposed to the beach is itself the primary activity.
Speaker 0: Now there is a game I've seen played on beaches a lot in recent years that I have not actually played myself I don't fully know the rules and that is the spike ball game Which is where you have the trampoline the mini trampoline and you throw the ball at it.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I don't quite know the rules to that, but I see people playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess long though and I see them.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're following any particular rules.
Speaker 1: I think they're just throwing stuff till they get bored.
Speaker 0: I think it's similar to like a four square to like you stand around the trampoline and you like Throw the ball at it and then it goes up in the air and someone else has to hit the ball at it again Right and it can't like touch the ground outside of it right sort of like a hacky sack situation.
Speaker 0: almost I don't know what the exact rules are.
Speaker 0: I could read them but what would be the point of that.
Speaker 0: you can read them yourself.
Speaker 0: if I want to I'll read them after the show.
Speaker 0: I've just seen it around and it seems to be popular at the beach and I you know, my guess Is that the reason it's popular to do that at the beach versus anywhere else is because just like with the beach volleyball You can mix in the diving and such without the risk of injury because the sand and not hard ground or Gymnasium floor or you know anything like that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think your main takeaway is not so much about the beach.
Speaker 1: But if you're the kind of nerd if you are commonly in situations The beach is just one example where you bring games to an event where it is hard to get other people to play games.
Speaker 1: Look around and look at what all your all the other people are doing.
Speaker 1: if they're engaging with the place You're at then that is the reason you are all there.
Speaker 1: Don't try to cram your terraforming forming Mars into that.
Speaker 1: That's why no one's playing terraforming Mars with you at the beach.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: and if you you know, if you're not at the beach to enjoy the beach Why are you there?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't go on a ski trip to not ski.
Speaker 0: Don't imagine if I went on the ski trip But I didn't want to ski and I just stayed in the lodge the whole time and I was like, hey guys Let's play.
Speaker 0: that's like some terraforming Mars But everyone I'd be waiting there for hours and hours.
Speaker 0: everyone else skis.
Speaker 0: then they finally get back and they're probably tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe they'll play a game.
Speaker 0: Probably not a terraforming Mars.
Speaker 1: I go a lot of ski trips and I learned to not even bring.
Speaker 1: I bring like Wizard at this point and that's yeah because even on the trip I went with all pros Whose means go Joe and paint like it was pros only.
Speaker 1: We played an average of one point one games per night before we fucking fell asleep.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: clue calm for show notes discussion links and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows Mondays or science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays gaming and games.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are arbitrary and Indiscriminate.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 4.0 International license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: the patreon patrons for this episode of geek nights RL enjoys link eg dread.
Speaker 1: lily Tenebrae case.
Speaker 1: care makes music.
Speaker 1: Chris hadad Christopher or Clinton Walton Finn Joel Hayes penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin von Horl and a bunch of people whose names I will not say.
Speaker 1: I Highly recommend you read the the justice Sotomayor's Dissents of the catastrophic Supreme Court decision.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna leave this little tidbit here for you.
Speaker 1: That's all I got for you tonight.
Speaker 1: You if you live in the United States and you can vote you really better vote for whoever the Democrats nominate No matter what cuz.
Speaker 1: there really isn't another option.
Speaker 1: Never in the history of our Republic as a president had reason to believe he'd be immune from criminal prosecution If he used the trappings of his office to violate the criminal law.
Speaker 1: moving forward However, all former presidents will be cloaked in such immunity If the occupant of that office misuses official power for personal gain.
Speaker 1: The criminal law that the rest of us must abide will not provide a backstop.
Speaker 1: and here's how she ends her dissent Katie.
Speaker 1: with fear for our democracy I Dissent.
Speaker 1: I mean, it doesn't get stronger than that Neil Have you ever heard?
Speaker 1: Have you ever?
Speaker 1: sorry to interrupt you but have you ever heard of justice be that strongly worded about the state of our democracy?
Speaker 1: I have not.
Speaker 1: and what she's signaling here is it's not just about the Trump January 6th case.
Speaker 1: It's about every president who goes forward and deep possibly Trump next year and being immune now from the criminal law To be able to use the Justice Department in wait.
Speaker 1: the court today calls Absolutely immune to undermine elections to go after individuals.
Speaker 1: This is a you know, according to the dissent which you know It was it seems like as grave a shift in our constitutional system as any in our lifetime.